<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Weilin&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://weilinshi.org/en/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Weilin&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>zh-cn</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 14:22:39 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://weilinshi.org/en/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Work From Home Thoughts</title>
      <link>http://weilinshi.org/en/post/work-from-home-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 14:22:39 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://weilinshi.org/en/post/work-from-home-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>Since I live in China and work from home since the beginning of Febuary, I should write down some random thoughts about work from home.
Busy or not? When you work at an office, if you need something from a person, you can just go to that person&amp;rsquo;s desk and have a direct conversion with him (or her). Now, when you work from home, the only thing you can do is to send someone a slack message.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Will Stop Maintain svg-captcha</title>
      <link>http://weilinshi.org/en/post/i-will-stop-maintain-svg-captcha/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2017 16:29:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://weilinshi.org/en/post/i-will-stop-maintain-svg-captcha/</guid>
      <description>Update March 2020 They don&amp;rsquo;t bother to answer issues or manage pull requests, fuck them.
What? I&amp;rsquo;m the former maintainer of Node.js open source captcha generation library svg-captcha.
As you can see, I&amp;rsquo;ve put a lot of effort in maintain the repo, as well as reply issues and merge pull requests. Since I no longer works at Lemonce, I&amp;rsquo;ve lost the access to the repo.
Li Chao will take over the maintaince of the library.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No JavaScript</title>
      <link>http://weilinshi.org/en/post/no-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2017 18:18:05 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://weilinshi.org/en/post/no-javascript/</guid>
      <description>Remove JS from my blog Almost every modern website requires JavaScript to function properly nowadays. At my day job, single page application is the way to build website. If you disable JS, good luck finding a website that is useful. And there is the debate over whether websites should suppport JavaScript-free mode. I&amp;rsquo;m not going to argue for that issue. I think that depend on your website&amp;rsquo;s content and your budget.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot</title>
      <link>http://weilinshi.org/en/post/godot/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 18:28:22 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://weilinshi.org/en/post/godot/</guid>
      <description>Godot engine Recently I finished my first android app for a client work. Although it make sound weird, I used a game engine called Godot for my app.
It is open sourced and released under the permissive MIT license. And it compiles to all desktop and mobile platform as you would expect from a game engine.
The development experience with Godot engine can be very &amp;ldquo;simple&amp;rdquo;. There is no third party library, package management, or make / bundle process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Typescript vs Flow</title>
      <link>http://weilinshi.org/en/post/typescript-vs-flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 11:40:57 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://weilinshi.org/en/post/typescript-vs-flow/</guid>
      <description>Update 2019-01-30
More than two years have passed since I wrote this. Right now the Typescript had grown a lot since then. I honestly think Typescript is a better choice today.
My experience with Typescript and Flow When it comes to type safety in Javascript projects, we have two choices available: Typescript and Flow.
People argued that Javascript does not have type checks and it often lead to some very hard to catch bugs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>svg captcha</title>
      <link>http://weilinshi.org/en/post/svg-captcha/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2016 11:16:29 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://weilinshi.org/en/post/svg-captcha/</guid>
      <description>svg captcha I use a windows laptop at works and it won&amp;rsquo;t compile any native c++ addons.
However, all of node&amp;rsquo;s captcha generation modules dependend on c++ addons in some ways. So I wrote a SVG captcha generation module.
github repository：https://github.com/lemonce/svg-captcha
Install：
 npm i &amp;ndash;save svg-captcha
 Usage:
var svgCaptcha = require(&amp;#39;svg-captcha&amp;#39;); // generate random text of length 4 var text = svgCaptcha.randomText(); // generate svg image var captcha = svgCaptcha(text);  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>